rvshare.com 2018-09-08

# Privacy Policy - RVshare

Last Updated: May 25, 2018

We are serious about protecting the privacy of our users. This Privacy Policy describes how we use and protect your personal data. It applies to RVShare.com and its related mobile application (which we have collectively called the “website” in this policy).The website is operated by RVshare, LLC (“RVshare” or the “Company,” “we,” or “us”).The terms “users” or “you” as used in this Privacy Policy, refer to renters who use the website to look for RVs to rent, Owners who use the website and list their RVs for rent, and general users who visit the website. 

Information we collect about you will be used in the manner explained in this Privacy Policy. The website may contain links to third parties' sites. We're not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those sites. Therefore, please read carefully any privacy policies on those sites before either agreeing to their terms or using those sites. Unless we explain otherwise in this policy, the words and phrases used in this Privacy Policy have the same meaning as in the Terms of Service for the website (the “Terms”).

By providing information to us when subscribing, contacting us or otherwise using the website, you expressly agree to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy applies from the date last upated as noted at the top of this page. We may occasionally amend this Privacy Policy to reflect regulatory requirements, advances in technology, website updates and changes in our information collection and disclosure practices. Any new policy will automatically be effective when it is published on the website. Your continued use of the website after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so you should therefore return here regularly to view our most up to date Privacy Policy. You should also print a copy for your records.

## Who Processes Your Personal Data and Where

Your personal data (also referred to as personal information) - that is, data that identifies you, or from which you are identifiable - will be collected, processed, stored and used by us, and passed to and processed by RVShare and other data processors acting under our instructions. By using our website, you acknowledge and agree that you may be transferring your personal data outside of the country in which you have contributed it (“your country”), and that you consent to any transfer of information outside of your country. These countries may not have similar data protection laws to those that apply in your country. However, if we transfer your personal data outside of your country in this way, we will take steps to try to ensure that your privacy rights are protected in compliance with applicable data protection law, this Privacy Policy, and the terms of our Safe Harbor self-certification.

Because RVShare does not pursue business in the European Union (“EU”), actively target or market goods and services to EU persons, actively engage in tracking and collecting information about EU residents online, or monitor and create profiles of EU persons that visit the website, we are not subject to the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”). If you are a EU resident, be aware that GDPR mandates and disclosure requirements will not apply to your use of the website.

## The Information We Gather

At various times you may give your personal data to us. For example, in order to process a request or inquiry from you, we may need to know all or some of the following: your full name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, your current location, and a method of payment. You may also give personal data to us at other times, such as when registering on the website or when submitting a Listing for an RV. We may also gather information from cookies or web beacons. You can find out more about how they operate in the relevant section of this policy below. We also collect IP addresses, mobile device identifier details, your location, navigation and click-stream data, the time of accessing the website, RVs you viewed, what you searched for, the duration of your visit, and other details of your activity on the website. If you ask us to connect with other sites (for example if you ask us to connect with your Facebook account) we may get information that way too. For further details on how we collect personal data, see below. We obtain data from you either by you inputting your personal details, by the automatic collection of information about you as you use the website, when we speak to you, or from third parties. Third party information may include credit information which we use to prevent and detect fraud, information from your mobile provider if you are accessing the website over a mobile device or information from a third party such as a social media or travel opinions site where you have asked us to share your data with them.

## How We Use Your Personal Data

Our primary purpose in collecting your personal data is to provide you with the Services you request and those which we believe will optimize your use of the website. You agree that we may use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * For the Services or to support your request;
  * To contact you from time to time with user or Service updates; 
  * To send other messages that help us provide our Services;
  * To assist people you have done business with. For example if you are an Owner and a Renter who has booked or inquired with you needs your details we may pass them on; if you are a Renter and an Owner you have booked with needs to contact you we may give them your details;
  * To customize, measure, report on and improve our services, content and advertising; 
  * To promote Services related to the website and/or our affiliates;
  * To compare information for accuracy, and verify it with third parties;
  * To prevent, investigate or prosecute activity we think may be potentially illegal, unlawful, or harmful; and 
  * To enfo rce our Privacy Policy and/or our Terms or any other purpose referenced herein or therein. 

We collate statistics about website traffic, sales and other commercial information which we pass onto third parties to assist us in improving the Services we provide to you. We also use demographic information to tailor the website and we share that information with third parties so that they can build up a better picture of our customer base and general consumer trends.If you are a Member, we may also contact you about your account and your use of our Services.

## How We May Disclose Your Personal Data

We may disclose your personal data to enforce our policies, or where we are permitted to do so by applicable law, such as in response to a request by a law enforcement or governmental authority, or in connection with actual or proposed litigation, or to protect our property, people and other rights or interests.

We may also share your personal data with:

  * One of our partners if you've requested their services or if you’ve requested to be provided with information by them;
  * Another User if you have done business with them;
  * A third party performing services on our behalf; 
  * Affiliated companies; 
  * Other companies or business entities, for example if we are thinking of a sale, merger, or other strategic transaction with or sale to that company or business entity; 
  * Other companies we work with to feature all or part of our Owner's RV Listings or otherwise provide promotional or other services related to our or business. This might include featuring your Listings and photographs on other websites; or
  * Any third party you have asked us to share your personal data with – such as Facebook, if you have asked us to connect with your Facebook account.

You may have accessed our website through a hyperlink from the site of one of our partners. If so, you consent to your personal details and purchase information, including behavioral patterns, being shared with that trading partner in accordance with our contractual relationship with them.

In the event that RVShare is sold, or some of its assets transferred to a third party, your personal information may also be transferred. Potential purchasers and their advisors may have access to data as part of the sale process. Similarly, your personal information may be passed on to a successor in interest in the unlikely event of a liquidation, bankruptcy, or administration. Our customer database could be sold separately from the rest of the business, in whole or in a number of parts. It could be that the purchaser's business is different from ours, too.

## Advertising Disclosure

We are a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn fees by linking to Amazon.com and affiliated websites.

## Newsletters

If you sign up as a Member on the website, you may receive our newsletter, which is an integral part of the Services we provide. Renters will be given the option to receive our Renter newsletter when they register with us. We may offer different newsletters from time to time intended to enhance the Services we offer. Users may cancel their subscription to these newsletters at any time, although it may take a short while for the changes in your preferences to become effective.

## Surveys

We also use surveys to collect information about our users. From time to time, we request users' input in order to evaluate potential features and services. The decision to answer a survey is completely yours. We use information gathered from surveys to improve our services.

## Games

From time to time we may run games on the website. These games may allow for connectivity with other users or third parties. If that is the case you consent to your personal data being transferred accordingly.

## Telephone Calls

As well as collecting data online and from correspondence we may also speak with you face to face (for example at an Owner’s meeting) or by telephone. We frequently record telephone conversations. Those recordings are also governed by this Privacy Policy and we keep this data in the same way that we keep other data. Recordings of calls may also be transferred between locations or processed worldwide.

## Inquiries

Renters may send inquiries to Owners via clickable links on the Listings on the website. If you choose to send an inquiry through these links, your personal information, including your email address and any other information you supply, will be visible to the Member in question so that they might reply directly to you. Your details may also be sent to us and we may have access to those communications even if you contact the Member directly. Additionally those messages may be hosted on, be processed by or transmitted through our servers. If you call the Member, you may be asked to leave a return telephone number. Do not share information in the e-mail or phone call that you are not prepared to allow the other Member and RVShare to have, including, but not limited to, credit card and bank account information. Inquiries can be sent to the individual Member you selected and to our system. The resulting inquiry is available for review by the Member to whom it was initially addressed and to our customer service people, who may share past inquiry information, or information related to past stays including your contact details with Members. We may also from time to time, use third party e-mail servers to send and track receipt of inquiry emails, and analyze the pattern of inquiry usage reported by these third-party tracking systems.

## How Do We Protect Your Personal Information Once We Have It?

We take reasonable technical and organizational measures to guard against unauthorized or unlawful processing of your personal data and against accidental loss or destruction of, or damage to, your personal data. While no system is completely secure, we believe the measures implemented by the website reduce our vulnerability to security problems to a level appropriate to the type of data involved. We have security measures in place to protect our user database and access to this database is restricted internally. However, it remains your responsibility:

  * To protect against unauthorized access to your website account; 
  * To ensure no-one else uses the website while your machine is logged on to the website (including by logging on to your machine through a mobile, Wi-Fi or shared access connection you are using); 
  * To log off or exit from the website when not using it; 
  * Where relevant, to keep your password or other access information secret. Your password and log-in details are personal to you and should not be given to anyone else or used to provide shared access for example over a network; and 
  * To maintain good internet security. For example if your email account or Facebook account is compromised this could allow access to your account with us if you have given us those details and/or permitted access through those accounts. If your email account is compromised it could be used to ask us to reset a password and gain access to your account with us. You should keep all of your account details secure. If you think that any of your accounts have been compromised you should change your account credentials with us, and in particular make sure any compromised account does not allow access to your account with us. You should also tell us as soon as you can, so that we can try to help you keep your account secure and if necessary warn anyone else who could be affected.

If you have asked us to share data with third party websites, however (such as Facebook), their servers may not be secure. Credit card information is generally stored by our credit card processing partners and we ask them to keep that data secure. We also use third parties to help us optimize our website flow, content and advertising (see below).Note that, despite the measures taken by us and the third parties we engage, the internet is not secure. As a result others may nevertheless unlawfully intercept or access private transmissions or data.

## What Are Cookies, Web Beacons and Clear GIFs and Why Do We Use Them?

A "cookie" is a small file placed on your hard drive by some of our web pages. We, or third parties we do business with, may use cookies to help us analyze our web page flow, customize our Services, content and advertising, measure promotional effectiveness and promote trust and safety. Cookies are commonly used at most major transactional websites in much the same way we use them here at our website.You may delete and block all cookies from this website, but parts of the website will not work.

Even if you are only browsing the website certain information (including computer and connection information, browser type and version, operating system and platform details, and the time of accessing the website) is automatically collected about you. This information will be collected every time you access the website and it will be used for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy.

You can reduce the information cookies collect from your device. An easy way of doing this is often to change the settings in your browser. If you do that you should know that (a) your use of the website may be adversely affected (and possibly entirely prevented), (b) your experience of this website and other sites that use cookies to enhance or personalize your experience may be adversely affected, and (c) you may not be presented with advertising that reflects the way that you use our website and other sites. You find out how to make these changes to your browser at www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will send cookies as soon as you visit our website. By using the website you consent to this, unless you change your browser settings. We gather and share information concerning the use of the website by users with one or more third-party tracking companies for the purpose of reporting statistics. To do this, some of the pages you visit on our website use electronic images placed in the web page code, called pixel tags (also called "clear GIFs" or "web beacons") that can serve many of the same purposes as cookies.

Web beacons may be used to track the traffic patterns of users from one page to another in order to maximize web traffic flow. Our third-party advertising service providers may also use web beacons to recognize you when you visit the website and to help determine how you found the website. If you would like more information about this and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp).

## Phishing or False emails

If you receive an unsolicited email that appears to be from us or one of our Members that requests personal information (such as your credit card, login, or password), or that asks you to verify or confirm your account or other personal information by clicking on a link, that email was likely to have been sent by someone trying to unlawfully obtain your information, sometimes referred to as a "phisher" or "spoofer." We do not ask for this type of information in an email. Do not provide the information or click on the link. Please contact us at [support@rvshare.com](mailto:support@rvshare.com) if you get an email like this.

## Job applicants, current and former employees

If you use the website to apply to work with us, we will use the information you supply to process your application and to monitor recruitment statistics. Where we want to disclose information to a third party, for example where we want to take up a reference, will not do so without informing you beforehand unless the disclosure is required by law. Personal information about unsuccessful candidates will be held for twelve (12) months after the recruitment exercise has been completed, it will then be destroyed or deleted. We retain de-personalized statistical information about applicants to help inform our recruitment activities, but individuals should not be identifiable from that data. RVShare is based in the US and employee and recruitment data is held there.

Once a person has taken up employment with us, we will compile a file relating to their employment. At that stage we will give you more details about how we store employee details.

## How do I correct or update my information?

You can see personal information processed by us. The best way of seeing this if you are an Owner is to log on to your account by using the ‘Owner Login’ tab at the top of the screen. You can see your basic details and correct or update them there at any time to suit you. We also want to give you the opportunity to identify any inaccuracies in any other information we hold about you. Where possible, if we're told about the inaccuracy of any personal information, we will make appropriate corrections. You can ask to see, update or amend any information we hold on you by contacting us.

## How do I opt-out of receiving marketing communications from you?

We will contact you from time to time for marketing purposes. Unless you have opted out, this could include contacting you by phone or email. You may opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us by the following means:

  1. Contact us at [support@rvshare.com](mailto:support@rvshare.com);
  2. Follow the instructions included in each communication or newsletter; or
  3. Mail a request to RVshare at P.O. Box 251, Bath, OH 44210-0251

Please remember that if you change your preferences it may take a short time for those preferences to become effective.

## Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Service that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [support@rvshare.com](mailto:support@rvshare.com), or write us at: RVshare LLC, P.O. Box 251, Bath, OH 44210-0251

## Children’s Issues

We will not knowingly collect any information from individuals under the age of 13. If you are under the minimum age required for use of the Services, do not use or provide any information on the Services or on or through any of its features, register on the Services, make any purchases through the Services, use any of the interactive or public comment features of the Services or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use. Should we determine that you do not meet the age requirements for using our Services, your registration will be terminated immediately. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a user under the required minimum age, we will delete that information.

## How long will we keep your personal data?

We will retain your personal data only as long as is necessary for the purposes to which you consent under the Terms and this Privacy Policy, or as is required by applicable law, and then we will delete it.

## How do I contact you?

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this website, or your dealings with this website, we encourage you to contact us at [support@rvshare.com.](mailto:support@rvshare.com)
